

Jan Stigliani

Date of birth: 21/12/2000 | **Nationality:** Italian | **Gender:** Male | **Phone number:**

(+39) 3451656064 (Mobile) | Email address: janstigli@gmail.com | Website:

https://janstigliani.altervista.org/ | Website: https://linktr.ee/jan_stigliani | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jan-stigliani-6a63a0229/ WhatsApp Messenger: +39 3451656064

Address: via Romualdo Tosi 18a, 16030, Castiglione Chiavarese, Italy (Home)

ABOUT ME

Hello, my name is Jan, and I am 24 years old. I aspire to establish myself as a Narrative Designer, driven by the belief that creating games is a form of art. Through this medium, I strive to express my creativity and craft stories that resonate deeply with people's emotions.

In December 2022, I earned a degree in Game Design and Development from Vigamus Academy in Rome. Currently, I am working as a Narrative and Game Designer on *Mind Scraper*, a graphic adventure developed by the independent team Scraper Games. The project won second prize in the 'Lazio Innova" contest and received valuable industry feedback from *One O One Games*. We showcased a demo at First Playable 2024 in Florence. I also pursue personal projects detailed in my portfolio: janstigliani.altervista.org.

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2023 - CURRENT Roma, Italy

NARRATIVE & GAME DESIGNER MIND SCRAPER TEAM

Mind Scraper is a graphic adventure game in development that delves into profound themes, exploring dreamlike journeys and challenging memories. As a **Narrative and Game Designer**, I was responsible for:

- World-building: Developing a detailed and cohesive narrative universe.
- Character development: Creating protagonists and secondary characters with deep and meaningful story arcs.
- Dialogue writing: Crafting texts that enhance the plot and improve player immersion.
- Level design: Designing levels that seamlessly integrate storytelling and gameplay.

The project won **second place in the "Lazio Innova" competition**, receiving valuable feedback from *One O One Games*, and was showcased at **First Playable 2024** in Florence.

Tools used: XMind, Google Docs, Articy Draft, Figma.

Game Engine: Unity

Business or Sector Arts, entertainment and recreation | **Department** Game Devolopment |

Email scraperteam.games@gmail.com | Website https://www.mindscrapergame.com/home

Links https://www.instagram.com/scrapergames/ | https://youtu.be/Yq4-3B_JKfU | https://janstigliani.altervista.org/

04/2024 - 09/2024 Sestri Levante, Italy

SHOP ASSISTANT MONDADORI

Address VIA XXV APRILE, 71/73, 16039, Sestri Levante, Italy

03/2017 - 09/2023 Cavi di Lavagna, Italy

HEAD WAITER (SEASONAL) BAGNI CIGNO

Address Via del Cigno, 16033, Cavi di Lavagna, Italy

CREATIVE WORKS

02/2023 - CURRENT

Mind Scraper

Mind Scraper is a videogame that I'm currently developing with Scraper Games. It's a graphic adventure that lets the player relive lifelong experiences throughout oniric voyages inside different minds. I'm the narrative designer and the game writer and I collaborate with Game designers for what concerns level design and mechanics.

Links https://janstigliani.altervista.org/ | https://youtu.be/Yq4-3B_JKfU

11/2024 - CURRENT

Arcanum: The Resistance

Arcanum: The Resistance is a graphic adventure I am developing using various AI tools. It's supposed to be a short story set in a fantasy world I created for a book contest. I am using Ren'py as the game engine and plan to integrate a turn-based combat system crafted in Python. As I said: characters, backgrounds and music are made with the help of AI.

Links https://youtu.be/X2tjk4X8YBE | https://youtu.be/aTnd0iHQJZ0

09/2022 - 12/2022

Cult of Immortality

This is the second personal project I worked on during my Unreal Engine course. It's developed on UE5 and it's a MetroidVania 2.5D built with assets from the Asset Store. The player has to face a complete level, filled with traps and enemies to reach the exit of a cave. I drafted documentation about world-building, characters, plot and level design before starting to work on the actual game.

Links https://janstigliani.altervista.org/ | https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OSvRnL TWqA

07/2022 - 09/2022

The Abandoned City of Ashkara

The construction of Ashkara is born as an exercise during summer vacation. I wanted to practise on Unreal Engine and I decided to create a map so I started to build a city and I did my best to make it seem as realistic as possible.

Links https://www.artstation.com/artwork/DARRBy | https://janstigliani.altervista.org/

The Ballad of Death and Wind

This is my first book, self-published on the Wattpad site a few years ago. The work was written during my last years of high school and was appreciated during literary competitions, such as "Io Scrittore". Currently, the production is in a state of deep revision and rewriting; so far only the first two chapters have been updated, but following work commitments, I am trying to finish work on the entire manuscript.

Link https://www.wattpad.com/1270635346-la-danza-della-morte-e-del-vento-spesso-il-vento

DIGITAL SKILLS

Design

Proficient in creative writing | Good knowledge of office suites | Figma Prototyping | Ability to draft working documents

Engines

Good knowledge of the fundamentals of Unreal Engine | Basic skills in the use of Unity

Soft Skills

Skilled in social relations and communication | Used to both networking and working alone | Problem-Solving (Problem Analysis)

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

03/2022 - 16/12/2022 Roma, Italy

TRAINING COURSE IN GAME DESIGN&DEVELOPMENT Vigamus Academy

- 1. Training in the use of game engines such as Unreal and Unity.
- $\hbox{2. Study regarding elements of Game-Design and Narrative-Design.}\\$

- 3. Creation of individual and group projects.
- 4. Conception and drafting of design documents.

Address 00166, Roma, Italy

Website https://www.vigamusacademy.com/?gclid=CjwKCAjwv4SaBhBPEiwA9YzZvCZoBuo26_3qDNr2O3mePFL4Xz3AfcRtUp2FlslPOo2bagU21Ka6RRoChvMQAvD_BwE

Field of study Game Industry

Links https://www.artstation.com/jan_stigliani_00

2014 - 2019 Chiavari, Italy

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA Liceo Marconi-Delpino

Specific skills in the field of science:

- -Logic
- -Physics
- -Mathematics
- -Chemistry
- -Biology

Field of study Scientifico | Final grade 70

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): ITALIAN

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	B2	B2	B2	B2	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Writing and Gaming

Film and TV series first, and games and books then, have always fascinated me for their ability to entertain through the stories they tell, and as I grew up, this feeling led me to want to write my own. I started creating short stories, character sheets, and world events, and then, in 2020 I decided to write a book, "The Ballad of Death and Wind", which I published on Wattpad.

After that writing experience, I understood that I wanted to make creative writing my job and I decided to combine it with my other passion: Videogames.

My passion for video games was born during my childhood with Pokemon Ruby on GameBoy and has continued to grow ever since. Games like Shadow of the Colossus, Final Fantasy IV, Detroit Become Human, The Last of Us and The Witcher 3 shaped my vision and made me fall in love with this medium and its completeness.

Blending these passions of mine gave birth to my aim of becoming a narrative designer.

Link https://janstigliani.altervista.org/